SATYAM SAGAR

Front End Developer

+91 9755345913

xatyamsagar30@gmail.com



github.com/satyam95





Bhopal, IND

SUMMARY

Front-end developer with 3+ years of experience building responsive websites using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Recently skilled up with React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, and react testing library. Contributed to company internal projects using these recent acquired skills. Proven ability to work independently and as part of a team. Strong attention to detail and commitment to quality.

EXPERIENCE

Wordpress Developer

Appointy India



2021 - Present



Bhopal, IND

- Used Test-Driven Development (TDD) principles to ensure code quality and reliability in a Next.js project, resulting in a robust and maintainable web application.
- Received a cash prize for exceptional performance in WordPress development, demonstrating my commitment to excellence in web development and my ability to consistently produce high-quality work.
- Designed and developed multiple custom WP Bakery components, which enhanced site functionality and user experience, seamlessly integrated into websites via a bespoke WordPress plugin.
- Technologies Next.js, Tailwind CSS, TypeScript, React Testing Library, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

Wordpress Developer - Intern

Adroitors SEO



i Oct 2019 – Apr 2020 🝳 Remote



Developed, maintained, and optimized e-commerce, business, blogging, and other websites using various page builders (such as WP Bakery, Elementor, Divi, and BeBuilder) and custom HTML/CSS templates.

PROJECTS

Ecommerce Web App - Flipkart's Clone

- Built with next.js and styled using Tailwind CSS, this web app closely mirrors Flipkart's design and functionality.
- It replicates an appealing homepage, category pages, and cart functionality. It also uses Stripe for payment processing, NextAuth.js for authentication and also has product filtering, sorting and search functionality.
- Technologies Next.js, Tailwind CSS, Redux toolkit, NextAuth, Stripe payment gateway.





TECH STACK

Programming Languages: JavaScript (ES6),

TypeScript, HTML, CSS

Libraries & Frameworks: React, Next.js,

React Testing Library, Tailwind CSS Tools & Platforms: Git, WordPress

Design: Figma, AdobeXd

EDUCATION

B.E & M. Tech in CSE

Dual Degree Integrate PG, RGPV, Bhopal, IND

2014 – 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

Complete React Developer Udemy

Responsive Web Design

freeCodeCamp